zando.co.za 2017-09-11

# Privacy Policy

### **Keep calm, your private information is safe with us!**

Zando will, at all times, keep your Personal Information confidential and will only process information that is required to enable us to perform our obligations and provide you with the best possible service! We take our customers privacy very seriously and will take all reasonable and required steps to protect your Personal Information. We will only collect and use your personal information as outlined below.

For the purpose of this clause, "Personal Information" shall be defined as detailed in the _Protection of Personal Information Act No. 4 of 2013 (POPI)._

## **1.** Processing of Personal Information

ZANDO undertakes not to sell, share or trade any personal information collected online. Personal information collected online will only be disclosed within our corporate group and service providers where required to perform a service to customers or improve your online experience.

If you sign up for Zando’s newsletters or marketing mailers, you expressly consent to Zando sending you marketing communications (which under normal circumstances will be one mailer per day, but may be more during special campaign and/or competition periods). You may unsubscribe to these marketing communications at any time by clicking on the link within the electronic marketing material or by contacting customer service or the Information Officer.

After placing an order Zando will send you transactional emails for the purpose of tracking your order and keeping you informed. When placing an order you consent to Zando contacting you for purposes relating to the order and performance of the purchase agreement. Transactional emails are not considered marketing communications and/or direct marketing.

Take note that Zando sometimes partner with other companies and institutions for promotions, campaigns and competitions. If you are subscribed to the third party database and consented to them sending you marketing material you may receive marketing material from the third party relating to Zando even if you have unsubscribed to Zando’s marketing material. Should a third party contact you with Zando marketing material without your consent, kindly report this to Zando ([legal@zando.co.za](mailto:legal@zando.co.za)) in order for us to investigate.

Any complaints regarding the processing of Personal Information may be sent to our Information Officer ( [legal@zando.co.za](mailto:legal@zando.co.za)) and will be addressed as a matter of urgency.

## 2\. Collection of Personal Information 

**2.1** When you create an account the personal information we collect may include your:

  * Name and Surname
  * Delivery Address
  * Email Address
  * Telephone Number
  * Mobile Number
  * Date of Birth
  * Gender
ID number / passport number 

If a refund is required we may request your bank account details in order to make payment.

**2.2** The Personal Information we collect from you will be used in some or all of the following ways:

  * To identify you
  * To deliver the products you have purchased from ZANDO
  * To update you on the delivery of the product and for customer support purposes
  * To provide you with relevant product information

**2.3** When you register as a user/customer on ZANDO’S website, we will also use your Personal Information to send you marketing and/or promotional materials from time to time. You can unsubscribe from marketing information at any time by using the unsubscribe function within the electronic marketing material, by contacting customer service or by contacting the Information Officer.

**2.4** Zando may also collect non-personal browsing habits and click patterns

## **3.** Updating Your Personal Information

You can update your Personal Information anytime by accessing your account on ZANDO’S website. 

## **4.** Security of Your Personal Information

ZANDO ensures that all information collected will be safely and securely stored. We protect your Personal Information by: 

  * Restricting access to personal information
  * Maintaining technology products to prevent unauthorised computer access
  * Securely destroying your personal information when it's no longer needed for our record retention purposes

ZANDO uses _128 - bit SSL (secure sockets layer) encryption technology_ when processing your financial details. 128-bit SSL encryption is approximated to take at least one trillion years to break, and is in line with the industry standard. ZANDO’S registration documents and the Site's registered domain name are checked and verified by DigiCert.

## 5\. Disclosure of Personal Information

**5.1** We will not share your information with any other organisations other than related companies and those third parties directly related to the delivery of the products you have purchased from ZANDO’S website.

**5.2** In exceptional circumstances ZANDO may be required to disclose Personal Information, such as when there are grounds to believe that the disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health, or for law enforcement purposes.

**5.3** ZANDO is committed to complying with the _Protection of Personal Information Act 4 of 2013_ as well as the _Promotion of Access to Information Act 2 of 2000_ and its principles.

**5.4** If you believe that your privacy has been breached by ZANDO please contact our Information Officer at [legal@zando.co.za](mailto:legal@zando.co.za) and we will resolve the issue.

## **6.** Collection of Computer Data

**6.1** Take note that our website makes use of “cookies” to automatically collect non-personal browsing habits and click patterns and to provide you with certain features on the website.

**6.2** If you do not wish for your information to be collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers which allows you to disable the cookie feature. If you do not disable the “cookie” feature, you consent to our use of the information collected by using that cookie.

**6.3** This information is collected for analysis and evaluation in order to help us improve our site and the services and products we provide. This data will not be used in association with any other Personal Information.

**6.4** When you visit Zando, our company servers will automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website, unless you disabled the “cookie” feature. This data may include:

  * Your computer's IP address
  * Browser type
  * Webpage you were visiting before you came to our site
  * The pages with ZANDO you visit
  * The time spent on those pages, items and information searched for on our site, access times and dates, and other statistics.

## **7.** Changes to the Privacy Policy

ZANDO reserves the right to modify and change the Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this policy will be published on our site. 

## **8.** Complaints about breaches of privacy

If you are not satisfied with the way in which we handle your Personal Information, please don't hesitate to contact us at [legal@zando.co.za](mailto:legal@zando.co.za)

## **9.** Remintrex

Remintrex is a web analysis service deployed by Remintrex GmbH, Adalbertstraße 5, 10999 Berlin, on behalf of cooperation partners. Remintrex is only deployed if you have given your consent, e.g. when registering for an internet promotion to a cooperation partner to send advertising via E-mail and/or SMS and/or to perform marketing calls to you and if you have also – as far as essential in the respective country and mandatory by law - agreed that Remintrex is deployed. Remintrex enables the cooperation partner to send advertising E-­‐Mails and/or SMS and/or to perform marketing calls matching the user behaviour on this website.

Remintrex uses cookies that are placed by the respective organiser, for instance for internet promotions, after the participant has given the organiser of the internet campaign his explicit consent to do so, if essential in the respective country and mandatory by law. When this website is visited the cookie sends a report to Remintrex GmbH as contract data processor of the cooperation partner that you (i.e. a user with the ID stored in the cookie) have visited the page, what product interested you and whether a contract came into being. The information is then stored separately for each individual cooperation partner on a server of Remintrex GmbH as contract data processor of the cooperation partners. With the communicated information Remintrex will – assuming you have agreed to receive advertising via E-­‐Mail and/or SMS and/or receive marketing calls and as far as essential in the respective country – be able to send you advertising E-­‐Mails and/or SMS and or to perform marketing calls on behalf of the cooperation partners and which give consideration to your user behaviour and thus also your interests.

The information communicated by the cookies will be used exclusively for advertising in which the products distributed on our pages are presented.

You can use your browser settings to delete the placed cookie at any time if you no longer wish for an analysis by Remintrex. You will find instructions about how to do this in the “Help” function of your browser.
